

101 Smith Hall, Pleasant St SE, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

□ (+1) 612-231-6989 | ■ pqh3.14@gmail.com | ♣ hungpham2017.github.io | ଢ hungpham2017 | ் hungpham-2017 |

"Think differently."

Summary_

I am a Research Assistant at the University of Minnesota, Twin Cities. My research interests focus on developing and applying new numerical techniques for periodic systems and strongly correlated materials. Working on variety of projects from theory to applications helps me earning skills and expertise in the fields of quantum embedding theories, wave function theories, density functional theory, structural chemistry and crystallography, photovotaics, and crystalline-framework materials. Check out my Google Scholar profile here 🗞

Education

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities

Ph.D. IN CHEMISTRY, ADVISOR: LAURA GAGLIARDI

Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

2015 - 2020 (expected)

VNUHCM-US (Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City - University of Science)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

2007 - 2011

Experience

University of Minnesota

B.S. IN CHEMISTRY, HONOR PROGRAM

Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Nov 2017 - Present

- Developed density matrix embedding theory for strongly correlated materials
- In silico design of lead-free perovskites for optoelectronic applications
- Theoretical study of light absorption and emission in the iridium complexes for OLED applications.

TEACHING ASSISTANT Sep 2015 - Dec 2016

- General Chemistry laboratories: CHEM 1017, CHEM 1065, CHEM 1066.
- CHEM 4021/8021: tutorials for OpenMolcas and CRYSTAL17, two lectures on the electronic structures for periodic systems.

Center for Molecular and NanoArchitecture (MANAR)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Oct 2011 Jul 2015
- Modeling and topological analysis in crystalline framework materials.

• Investigated gas adsorption in metal-organic frameworks, zeolite imidazole framework.

Institute for Computational Science and Technology (ICST)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

• Investigated the band-gap engineering in metal-organic frameworks.

VNUHCM-US Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

· Courses: General Chemistry laboratory, Physical Chemistry laboratory, Computational Chemistry laboratory.

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

Skills

Programming

- Python, C/C++, Fortran90, OpenMP
- Git, ATEX

Softwares

- PySCF, VASP, CRYSTAL, Gaussian, Quantum Espresso
- · Visualization: Crystal Maker, Materials Studio

Software development

pDMET (https://github.com/hungpham2017/pDMET)

DESCRIPTION

· A program to study electronic structure of periodic systems and materials by means of density matrix embedding theory. pDMET utilizes electron integrals and quantum-chemistry solvers from PySCF.

MCU (https://github.com/hungpham2017/mcu)

DESCRIPTION

 A Python package to analyze the periodic wave functions from electronic structure calculations. MCU supports a variety of electronic structure codes, such as: VASP, Quantum Espresso, CRYSTAL, PySCF, wannier90, etc.

pyWannier90 (https://github.com/hungpham2017/pyWannier90)

DESCRIPTION

 A Python interface for wannier90 used to construct the maximally-localized Wannier functions. pyWannier90 currently supports PySCF and VASP.

Publications

- 1. Q. Sun, ..., H. Q. Pham, ..., G. K.-L. Chan; Recent Developments in the PySCF Program Package, J. Chem. Phys, 2020, Accepted. %
- 2. **H. Q. Pham**, M. R. Hermes, L. Gagliardi; *Periodic Density Matrix Embedding Theory: A Wave Function Approach for Strongly Correlated Materials*, **J. Chem. Theory Comput.**, 2020, 16, 130. %
- 3. R. Sanner, N. Cherepy, **H. Q. Pham**, V. Young; *Phosphorescent Heteroleptic Iridium (III) Cyclometallates: Improved Syntheses of Acetylace-tonate Complexes and Quantum Chemical Studies of Their Excited State Properties*, **Polyhedron**, 2020, 176, 114256. %
- 4. **H. Q. Pham***, D. Q. Le, N.-N. Pham-Tran, Y. Kawazoe, D. Nguyen-Manh; *Electron Delocalization in Single-Layer Phthalocyanine-Based Covalent Organic Frameworks: A First Principle Study*, **RSC Advances**, 2019, 9, 29440. %
- 5. R. Sanner, N. Cherepy, H.P. Martinez, H. Q. Pham, V. Young; Highly Efficient Phosphorescence From Cyclometallated Iridium(III) Compounds: Improved Syntheses of Picolinate Complexes and Quantum Chemical Studies of Their Electronic Structures, Inorganica Chim. Acta, 2019, 496, 119040.
- 6. **H. Q. Pham**, R. J. Holmes, E. S. Aydil, L. Gagliardi; *Lead-Free Double Perovskites Cs*₂*InCuCl*₆ and (CH₃NH₃)₂*InCuCl*₆: Electronic, Optical, and Electrical Properties, Nanoscale, 2019, 11, 11173. 8
- 7. **H. Q. Pham**, V. Bernales, L. Gagliardi; Can Density Matrix Embedding Theory with the Complete Active Space Self-Consistent Field Solver Describe Single and Double Bond Breaking in Molecular Systems?, **J. Chem. Theory Comput.**, 2018, 14, 1960. %
- 8. D. Ray, C. Clarke, **H. Q. Pham**, J. Borycz; T. Zhang, E. S. Aydil, R. J. Holmes, L. Gagliardi; *A Computational Study of Structural and Electronic Properties of Lead-Free CsMI*₃ *Perovskites (M = Ge, Sn, Pb, Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba)*, **J. Phys. Chem. C**, 2018, 122, 7838. **%**
- 9. P. T. K. Nguyen, H. T. D. Nguyen, **H. Q. Pham**, J. Kim, K. E. Cordova, H. Furukawa; *Synthesis and Selective CO*₂ *Capture Properties of a Series of Hexatopic Linker-Based Metal-Organic Frameworks*, **Inorg. Chem.**, 2015, 54 (20), 10065.
- 10. T. L. H. Doan, H. L. Nguyen, **H. Q. Pham**, N.-N. Pham-Tran, T. N. Le, K. E. Cordova; *Tailoring the Optical Absorption of Water-Stable Zr*^{IV-} and Hf^{IV-}-Based Metal-Organic Framework Photocatalysts, **Chem. Asian J.**, 2015, 10, 2660. %
- 11. **H. Q. Pham**, T. Mai, N.-N. Pham-Tran, Y. Kawazoe, H. Mizuseki, D. Nguyen-Manh; *Engineering of Band Gap in Metal–Organic Frameworks by Functionalizing Organic Linker: A Systematic Density Functional Theory Investigation*, **J. Phys. Chem. C**, 2014, 118 (9), 4567. %

Presentations

The 4th International Workshop on Nanotechnology and Application - IWNA

Vung Tau, Vietnam

ORAL

Nov. 2013

• Engineering of Band Gap in Metal-Organic Frameworks by Functionalizing Organic Linker.

Chimie et Matériaux Avancés pour Environnement - CMAE2015

Hanoi, Vietnam

Oral

Jun. 2015

• Engineering of Band Gap in Crystalline Framework Materials via Functionalizing Organic Linker.

MolSSI Workshop for Python Simulation Software

Pasadena, CA, USA

ORAL

 $\bullet \quad \text{Multiconfigurational Wave Function Methods for Periodic Systems via Density Matrix Embedding Theory.}\\$

Y 1. 2020 HUNG O. PHAM · CURRICULUM VITAE

Jun. 2018

JULY 1, 2020

256th ACS National Meeting Boston, MA, USA

Oral

Multiconfigurational Wave Function Methods for Periodic Systems via Density Matrix Embedding Theory.

APS March Meeting 2019

Boston, MA, USA

ORAI

Mar. 2019

Aug. 2018

• Density Matrix Embedding Theory for Strongly Correlated Solids.

The 3th International Workshop on Nanotechnology and Application - IWNA Vung Tau, Vietnam

Poster

POSTER

Nov. 2011

• Mixed-linker based zeolitic imidazolate frameworks: Solvothermal synthesis and Computer simulation.

2016 All-Hands Meeting and Reaction Mechanisms Workshop

Poster

St. Paul, MN, USA

Aug. 2016

Vietnam

• Metal exchange in the zirconia node of NU-1000 for catalysis.

Minnesota Supercomputing Research Exhibition 2017

Minneapolis, MN, USA

Oct 2017

• Metal exchange in the zirconia node of NU-1000 for catalysis.

Minnesota Workshop on ab initio Modeling in Solid State Chemistry with Crystal 2017

Minneapolis, MN, USA

POSTER Jul. 2017

• A Novel Double Perovskite Cs. InCuCl₆: First-principles Study on Electronic, Optical, and Electrical Transport Properties.

Service to the community _____

Reviewing activities

- Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation, ACS %
- Solid State Communications, Elsevier %
- New Journal of Chemistry, RSC

Honors & Awards

2015 Vietnam Education Foundation (VEF) Fellowship, VEF (declined)

2008 **Lawrence S. Ting Scholarship**, Lawrence Ting Memorial Fund *Vietnam*

2008-2011 Academic Excellent Scholarship, VNUHCM-US Vietnam

Referees_

Laura Gagliardi

McKnight Presidential Endowed Chair, Distinguished McKnight University Professor, Director

INORGANOMETALLIC CATALYST DESIGN CENTER

· University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA

Christopher J. Cramer

VICE PRESIDENT FOR RESEARCH, DISTINGUISHED MCKNIGHT UNIVERSITY PROFESSOR

• University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA